Brother against brother, father against son. All
competing for...THE COOLANGATTA GOLD!
The Coolangatta Gold is a drama film directed by Igor Auzins.
Steve Lucas is a nineteen year old who is filled with the burning
resentment of being forced to live in his brother's shadow.
His brother Adam, is burdened by his father's desire for glory, and must win The Coolangatta Gold Tri-Aquathon, It is the greatest endurance test of them all: a marathon involving
a 20 kilometer beach run, 6 kilometer swim and a 17 kilometer surf ski from Surfers Paradise along the golden arc of beach to Coolangatta and back to the start.
The Coolangatta Gold is a story of human endeavor and
endurance against overwhelming odds.
Steve Lucas, played by Joss McWilliam.
Adam Lucas, played by Colin Friels.
Joe Lucas, played by Nick Tate.
Kerri Dean, played by Josephine Smulders.
Robyn Lucas, played by Robyn Nevin.
Grant, played by Grant Kenny.
The Coolangatta Gold is a 1984 Australian film directed by Igor
Auzins and written by Peter Schreck and Ted Robinson.
It led to the establishment of the iron man race The Coolangatta
Gold in Coolangatta, on the Gold Coast, Queensland.
The film explores themes of underdog, obsession,
plantation, training, motorcycle crash.
The tone is emotional.